potsdam.edu 2014-06-29

# Privacy Policy

  Web Site Privacy

  **Privacy Protection  
** At SUNY Potsdam, we are committed both to protecting individuals' privacy and to allowing individuals and businesses to interact more easily with SUNY Potsdam. We recognize that visitors must be confident that their privacy is protected when they visit an official SUNY Potsdam web site. Visitors can travel through most of an official SUNY Potsdam web site without offering any information about themselves. Sometimes SUNY Potsdam does need information to provide services, often at the request of visitors , and this policy explains our online information practices. 

SUNY Potsdam does not collect any personal information about visitors unless they provide that information voluntarily by sending an e-mail, completing one of several online forms, or completing an online transaction. 

  This policy is consistent with the provisions of the [NYS Internet Security and Privacy Act](http://www.oft.state.ny.us/ecommerce/internet_security_privacy.htm), the Freedom of Information Law, and the Personal Privacy Protection Law. 

  **Information Collected Automatically When You Visit an Official SUNY Potsdam Web Site  
** When you visit an official SUNY Potsdam web site, SUNY Potsdam automatically collects and stores the following information about your visit: 

  *     The Internet Protocol (IP) address of the computer that accessed our web site  
  *     The type of browser, its version and the operating system on which that browser is running  
  * The web page from which the user's computer accessed the current web page and the web page at which the user entered an official SUNY Potsdam web site 
  *     The date and time of the user's request  
  *     The pages that were visited and the amount of time spent at an official SUNY Potsdam web site  
  *     The size of the content, in bytes, of any file or document sent to the user's computer  
  *     The country where your computer resides  
  * Search engines that brought users to an official SUNY Potsdam web site and the text search strings that allowed users to find an official SUNY Potsdam web site 
  *     Downloads the user requested (e.g., .pdf and .mov files) from an official SUNY Potsdam web site  

None of the above-mentioned information is deemed to constitute personal information by the NYS Internet Privacy and Security Act. The information that is collected automatically is used to improve the content of official SUNY Potsdam web sites and to help SUNY Potsdam understand how users are interacting with its web sites. This information is collected for statistical analysis and to determine what information is of most and least interest to our users. The information is not collected for commercial marketing purposes and SUNY Potsdam does not sell or otherwise disclose the information collected from an official SUNY Potsdam web site for commercial marketing purposes. 

  **Information Collected When You E-Mail an Official SUNY Potsdam Web Site or Complete a Transaction**  
During your visit to an official SUNY Potsdam web site, you may send an e-mail to SUNY Potsdam. Your e-mail address and the contents of your message will be collected. The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and graphic information formats attached to or included in the message. Your e-mail address and the information included in your message will be used to respond to you, to address issues you identify, to improve this web site, or to forward your message to another SUNY Potsdam employee for appropriate action. Your e-mail address is not collected for commercial purposes and SUNY Potsdam does not sell or otherwise disclose your e-mail address for commercial purposes. 

During your visit to an official SUNY Potsdam web site, you may complete a transaction such as a request to establish an internship, an update of your alumni information, or a gift to the College. The information collected by SUNY Potsdam, including personal information volunteered by you in completing the transaction, is used by SUNY Potsdam to operate our programs and may be disclosed by SUNY Potsdam for those purposes that may be reasonably ascertained from the nature and terms of the transaction in which the information was submitted. 

SUNY Potsdam does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 14 or create profiles of children under the age of 14. Users are cautioned, however, that the collection of personal information submitted in an e-mail will be treated as though it were submitted by an adult, and may, unless exempted from access by federal or State law, be subject to public access. We encourage parents and adult family to be involved in children's Internet activities and to provide guidance whenever children are asked to provide personal information online. 

  **Disclosure of Information Collected through an Official SUNY Potsdam Web Site**  
The collection of information through an official SUNY Potsdam web site and the disclosure of that information are subject to the provisions of the [NYS Internet Security and Privacy Act](http://assembly.state.ny.us/leg/?cl=114&a=3). Only if you have consented to the collection or disclosure of personal information will SUNY Potsdam collect your personal information through an official SUNY Potsdam web site or disclose your personal information collected through an official SUNY Potsdam web site. Your voluntary disclosure of personal information to SUNY Potsdam constitutes consent to the collection and disclosure of the information by SUNY Potsdam for the purposes for which you disclosed the information to SUNY Potsdam. 

However, SUNY Potsdam may collect or disclose personal information without consent if the collection or disclosure is: (1) necessary to perform the statutory duties of SUNY Potsdam, or necessary for SUNY Potsdam to operate a program authorized by law, or authorized by state or federal statute or regulation; (2) made pursuant to a court order or by law; (3) for the purpose of validating the identity of the user; or (4) of information to be used solely for statistical purposes that is in a form that cannot be used to identify any particular person. 

Further, the disclosure of information, including personal information, collected through an official SUNY Potsdam web site is subject to the provisions of the Freedom of Information Law and the Personal Privacy Protection Law. 

SUNY Potsdam may disclose personal information to federal or state law enforcement authorities to enforce its rights against unauthorized access or attempted unauthorized access to SUNY Potsdam's information technology assets. 

  **Retention of Information Collected through an Official SUNY Potsdam Web Site**  
The information collected through an official SUNY Potsdam web site is retained by SUNY Potsdam in accordance with the records retention and disposition requirements of the New York State Arts & Cultural Affairs Law. Information concerning these records retention and disposition schedules may be obtained through the Internet privacy policy contact listed in this policy. 

  **Access to and Correction of Personal Information Collected through an Official SUNY Potsdam Web Site**  
Any user may submit a request to SUNY Potsdam's privacy compliance officer to determine whether personal information pertaining to that user has been collected through an official SUNY Potsdam web site. Any such request shall be made in writing and must be accompanied by reasonable proof of identity of the user. Reasonable proof of identity may include verification of a signature, inclusion of an identifier generally known only to the user, or similar appropriate identification. The address of the privacy compliance officer is: 

>  
> 
>     Privacy Compliance Officer  
> SUNY Potsdam  
> Office of Public Affairs  
> 44 Pierrepont Ave.  
> Raymond Hall 604  
> Potsdam, New York 13676  

The privacy compliance officer shall, within five (5) business days of the receipt of a proper request, provide access to the personal information; deny access in writing, explaining the reasons therefore; or acknowledge the receipt of the request in writing, stating the approximate date when the request will be granted or denied, which date shall not be more than thirty (30) days from the date of the acknowledgment. 

In the event that SUNY Potsdam has collected personal information pertaining to a user through an official SUNY Potsdam web site and that information is to be provided to the user pursuant to the user's request, the privacy compliance officer shall inform the user of his or her right to request that the personal information be amended or corrected under the procedures set forth in section 95 of the Public Officers Law. 

  **Confidentiality and Integrity of Personal Information Collected through an Official SUNY Potsdam Web Site**  
SUNY Potsdam is strongly committed to protecting personal information collected through an official SUNY Potsdam web site against unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Consequently, SUNY Potsdam limits employee access to personal information collected through an official SUNY Potsdam web site to only those employees who need access to the information in the performance of their official duties. Employees who have access to this information follow appropriate procedures in connection with any disclosures of personal information. 

In addition, SUNY Potsdam has implemented procedures to safeguard the integrity of its information technology assets, including, but not limited to, authentication, authorization, monitoring, auditing, and encryption. These security procedures have been integrated into the design, implementation, and day-to-day operations of official SUNY Potsdam web sites as part of our continuing commitment to the security of electronic content as well as the electronic transmission of information. 

For web site security purposes and to maintain the availability of official SUNY Potsdam web sites for all users, SUNY Potsdam employs software to monitor traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise damage an official SUNY Potsdam web site. 

  **Cookies**  
Cookies are simple text files that are stored by your browser on the hard drive of your computer. The official SUNY Potsdam web sites do not use cookies. 

  **Disclaimer**  
The information provided in this privacy policy should not be construed as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail proof the security of information provided through an official SUNY Potsdam web site. 

  **Contact Information**  
For questions regarding this Internet privacy policy, please contact the SUNY Potsdam privacy compliance officer via e-mail at [relations@potsdam.edu](mailto:relations@potsdam.edu) or by regular mail at: 

>  
> 
>     Privacy Compliance Officer  
> SUNY Potsdam  
> Office of Public Affairs  
> 44 Pierrepont Ave.  
> Raymond Hall 604  
> Potsdam, New York 13676  

  **Definitions**  
The following definitions apply to this policy: 

  _Personal information:_ For purposes of this policy, "personal information" means any information concerning a natural person which, because of name, number, symbol, mark, or other identifier, can be used to identify that natural person. 

  _User:_ shall have the meaning set forth in subdivision 8 of section 202 of the State Technology Law. 

  _An official SUNY Potsdam web site:_ For purposes of this policy, "an official SUNY Potsdam web site" means a web site that serves an external audience beyond SUNY Potsdam faculty, staff, and current students, that is, www.potsdam.edu and http://bearpaws.potsdam.edu/prd/hwskwpro.P_WebProspectMain?  
prel_code_in=WEBF&button_text_in=Continue (the inquiry forms for prospective transfers and freshmen). Depending on SUNY Potsdam web site development and growth, this definition is subject to change at any time. To learn exactly which domains are official SUNY Potsdam web sites at this time, contact the Privacy Compliance Officer at the address listed above.
